first the breaking news from america tonight
as two members of the national guard have
been shot in washington close to the white
house now the suspect is severely wounded and
in custody sarah smith has the very latest
police surrounded the scene as we can see
someone being loaded into an ambulance
two members of the national guard were shot
on this busy street in central washington just
two blocks away from the white house
both of the guardsmen are said to have
been critically injured the suspected gunman was shot
at the scene and is in custody in
hospital
the vice president was addressing us troops in
kentucky when he got the news but apparently
there was a shooting outside the white house
just a couple of hours ago
and we're still learning everything we still don't
know the motive there's a lot that we
haven't yet figured out but what we do
know is that a couple of national guardsmen
were injured in the line of duty
the gunman is said to have been severely
wounded and there is now an extensive investigation
underway
i hear two shot it's boom boom
then after that
rainbow
came yeah like a hop off a raffle
this
is big fight
it was it was loud
the fbi chief praised the swift response from
law enforcement president trump has been informed we've
been in contact with the white house we
will bear we will shortchange the american public
with no resources
to make sure we find and safeguard our
nation's capital right here in washington dc and
bring anyone responsible for this heinous act of
violence to justice
two thousand national guard troops have been stationed
in washington for the last four months
and it has just been announced an extra
five hundred will be deployed to the city
sarah smith bbc news washington
tom bateman is live there for us now
tom bring us up to date with the
latest
well witnesses as we arrived here clive shortly
after the shooting described a scene of utter
panic remember we're just a block from the
white house here this was mid afternoon
people spoke to me about racing from the
scene as they heard a burst of gunfire
break out some people fleeing for shelter
in a liquor store nearby
now we have had an update as you
heard there from kash patel of the fbi
and other authorities in the last half an
hour they described this as a gunman coming
around the corner from a metro station and
in their words ambushing two national guard troops
in what they have described as a targeted
attack
now of course their investigation is in a
very initial stage but they will be taking
into account
the fact that the deployment of national guard
troops into american cities by president trump has
been a highly contentious
political move and that coming in the environment
also
of growing political violence in this country but
the authorities to be clear were asked about
any motive and at this stage they've given
no response to that question